Guide to the Letters in an Extra-Illustrated Copy of Representative Poems of Living Poets
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Letters in an extra-illustrated copy of Representative Poems of Living Poets
1884-1886
YCAL MSS 141
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
3 volumes
Consists of an extra-illustrated copy that includes letters and signatures.
liii, 683 p.
23 cm
Gilder, Jeannette L. (Jeannette Leonard), 1849-1916
Lathrop, George Parsons, 1851-1898
Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Consists of an extra-illustrated copy of Representative poems of living poets, American and English: selected by the poets themselves that includes letters and signatures.
American poetry; English poetry
- List of letters as they appear in three volumes
  - Volume I
    - Lowell, James Russell, 1885 Sep 17 (Box 1)
    - Carey, William, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey, 1885 Mar 17 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Elizabeth Akers, 1885 May 19 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Elizabeth Akers, 1885 Mar 24 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Elizabeth Akers, 1885 Sep 19 (Box 1)
    - Arnold, Edwin, 1885 Apr 8 (Box 1)
    - Arnold, Matthew, 1885 Mar 23 (Box 1)
    - Boker, George H., 1885 Mar 16 (Box 1)
    - Botta, Anne C. Lynch, Mar 27 (Box 1)
    - Boyeson, H. H., 1885 Jun 30 (Box 1)
    - Boyeson, H. H., 1885 Jul 12 (Box 1)
    - Bradley, Mary, 1885 Sep 11 (Box 1)
    - Browning, Robert, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Bunner, H. C., 1885 Apr (Box 1)
    - Burroughs, John, 1885 Mar (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      comment on note from Jeannette L. Gilder
    - Butler, William Allen, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Carleton, Will, 1885 Apr 21 (Box 1)
    - Cone, Helen Gray, 1885 Apr 30 (Box 1)
    - Cone, Helen Gray, 1885 Nov 6 (Box 1)
    - Coxe, A. Cleveland [Arthur Cleveland], Mar 26 (Box 1)
    - Craik, Dinah Maria Mulock, 1885 Apr 20 (Box 1)
    - Coxe, Arthur Cleveland, 1885 Jul 18 (Box 1)
    - Cranch, Christopher Pearse, 1885 Mar 26 (Box 1)
    - Curtis, George Washington, 1885 Mar 31 (Box 1)
    - Dana, Charles A. [Charles Anderson], 1885 Mar 24 (Box 1)
  - Volume II
    - De Vere, Aubrey, 1885 Apr 26 (Box 1)
    - Dobson, Austin, 1885 Mar 26 (Box 1)
    - Dobson, Austin, 1885 Apr 11 (Box 1)
    - Dodge, Mary Mapes, 1885 Apr 16 (Box 1)
    - Dorr, Julia C. R., 1885 Apr 14 (Box 1)
    - Dorr, Julia C. R., 1885 May 6 (Box 1)
    - Dowden, Edward, 1885 Apr 11 (Box 1)
    - English, Thomas Dunn, 1886 Mar 11 (Box 1)
    - English, Thomas Dunn, 1885 Apr 19? (Box 1)
    - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1885 Mar 27 (Box 1)
    - Gosse, Edmund, 1885 Mar 12 (Box 1)
    - Gosse, Edmund, 1885 Mar 17 (Box 1)
    - Guiney, Louise Imogen, 1885 Apr 16 (Box 1)
    - Hay, John, Jun 6 (Box 1)
    - Hayne, Paul Hamilton, Apr 1 (Box 1)
    - Harte, Bret, 1885 May 3 (Box 1)
    - Harte, Bret, 1885 May 25 (Box 1)
    - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1885 Apr 14 (Box 1)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1885 Mar 10 (Box 1)
    - Howe, Julia Ward, 1885 Jul 18 (Box 1)
    - Howells, William Dean, 1885 Apr 14 (Box 1)
    - Ingelow, Jean, n.d. (Box 1)
    - De Kay, Charles, n.d. (Box 1)
    - De Kay, Charles, 1885 Dec 30 (Box 1)
    - Lang, Andrew, Mar 26 (Box 1)
    - Lang, Andrew, Apr 20 (Box 1)
    - Larcom, Lucy, 1885 Apr 20 (Box 1)
    - Lathrop, George Parsons, 1885 Sep 7 (Box 1)
    - Lathrop, George Parsons, 1886 Mar 21 (Box 1)
    - Lazarus, Emma, Apr 18 (Box 1)
    - Leland, Charles Godfrey, 1884 May 8 (Box 1)
    - Leland, Charles Godfrey, 1885 May 27 (Box 1)
    - Locker-Lampson, Frederick, 1885 Mar 15 (Box 1)
    - Locker-Lampson, Frederick, 1885 Apr 18 (Box 1)
    - Lowell, James Russell, 1885 Jul 28 (Box 1)
    - Lowell, James Russell, 1885 Oct 1 (Box 1)
    - Lowell, James Russell, 1885 Nov 17 (Box 1)
    - Lowell, James Russell, 1885 Nov 27 (Box 1)
  - Volume III
    - Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron, 1885 Apr 8 (Box 1)
    - Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron, 1885 May 20 (Box 1)
    - Macdonald, George, 1885 May 3 (Box 1)
    - Mackay, Charles, 1885 Mar 30 (Box 1)
    - Marston, Philip Bourke, 1885 Apr 11 (Box 1)
    - Miller, Joaquin, 1885 Apr 23 (Box 1)
    - Phelps, Elizabeth Stuart, 1885 Apr 22 (Box 1)
    - Piatt, John James, 1885 May 26 (Box 1)
    - Powers, Horatio Nelson, 1885 Apr 6 (Box 1)
    - Powers, Horatio Nelson, 1885 May 4 (Box 1)
    - Powers, Horatio Nelson, 1886 Mar 10 (Box 1)
    - Powers, Horatio Nelson, 1886 Mar 11 (Box 1)
    - Preston, Margaret Junkin, Apr 24 (Box 1)
    - Proctor, Edna Dean, May 18 (Box 1)
    - Rossetti, Christina Georgina, 1885 Apr 20 (Box 1)
    - Savage, Minot J., 1885 Apr 17 (Box 1)
    - Spofford, Harriet Elizabeth Prescott, Apr 26 (Box 1)
    - Stedman, Edmund Clarence, 1885 Apr 27 (Box 1)
    - Stevenson, Robert Louis, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Stoddard, Elizabeth, n.d. (Box 1)
      Signature only
    - Stoddard, Richard Henry, 1885 Apr 15 (Box 1)
    - Story, William Wetmore, 1885 May 18 (Box 1)
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1885 Apr 15 (Box 1)
    - Taylor, Henry, 1885 Jun 10 (Box 1)
    - Tennyson, Hallam Tennyson, Baron, n.d. (Box 1)
      re: poems by Alfred Tennyson, Baron Tennyson
    - Macmillan & Co. [to Frederick Locker?], 1885 Mar 14 (Box 1)
    - Tennyson, Hallam Tennyson, Baron, 1885 Mar 12 (Box 1)
    - Thaxter, Celia, 1885 Apr 18 (Box 1)
    - Thomas, Edith Matilda, 1885 Apr 15 (Box 1)
    - Thompson, Maurice, 1885 Mar (Box 1)
    - Townsend, Mary Ashley, 1885 Aug 6 (Box 1)
    - Townsend, Mary Ashley, 1885 Aug 14 (Box 1)
    - Trowbridge, J. T. [John Townsend], 1885 Apr 17 (Box 1)
    - Whitman, Walt, 1886 Aug 9 (Box 1)
      Envelope only
    - Whitney, A. D. T. [Adeline Dutton Train], 1885 Apr 21 (Box 1)
    - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1885 Mar 12 (Box 1)
    - Winter, William, 1885 Jul 29 (Box 1)
    - Newman, John Henry, 1885 Apr 17 (Box 1)
    - Symonds, John Addington, 1885 May 10 (Box 1)
    - Collyer, Robert, 1885 Oct 10 (Box 1)
    - Chadwick, John White, 1885 Mar 28 (Box 1)
    - Savage, Minot J., 1886 Mar 11 (Box 1)
    - Jackson, Helen Hunt, 1885 Apr 29 (Box 1)
    - Hawthorne, Julian, 1885 Apr 15 (Box 1)
    - Hawthorne, Julian, 1885 Apr 28 (Box 1)
    - Stoddard, Richard Henry, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Watts-Dunton, Theodore, 1885 Apr 20 (Box 1)